<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <item>
      <title>Dracula Returns to Derby</title>
      <description>
        As we mark this centenary year, Derby celebrates the diverse incarnations of Dracula, from Bela Lugosi to Blackula.
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7217/1325/8148/DRTD_Bela_Lugosi_linocut_by_Mat_Pringle_Lo_Res_Web_artwork_tumb_2.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Dracula Returns to Derby"/></p>
        <p><strong>Dracula Returns to Derby</strong></p>
        <p>In 1924, the iconic theatrical adaptation of Dracula made its world premiere right here in Derby. But when the curtain rose, the monstrous figure from the novel had transformed. Derby's Dracula was no longer a terrifying creature, but a suave and charming figure, donning evening attire and an elegant opera cloak. This depiction became the blueprint for Hollywood's Dracula, captivating audiences worldwide.</p>

        <p>As we mark this centenary year, Derby celebrates the diverse incarnations of Dracula, from Bela Lugosi to Blackula. Keep an eye out for an array of events and workshops throughout the city, spanning from 2024 into 2025.</p>

        <p>This initiative is part of an AHRC research project led by the University of Derby in collaboration with Derby Museums, Sheffield Hallam University, and Bournemouth University.</p>

        <p>Join us in exploring the fascinating evolution of this timeless character!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Various Derby locations<br/>
        Street: <!-- Not Provided --><br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: <!-- Not Provided -->
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/dracula-returns-to-derby</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/dracula-returns-to-derby</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 23:59:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derby Comedy Club</title>
      <description>
        £14 per ticket 2 for £24 add food for £10 per person
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7617/2828/5516/Derby_Comedy_Club_logo.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Derby Comedy Club"/></p>
        <p>Welcome to the popular and entertaining Derby Comedy Club, home once a month to everything hilarious! Our nights consist of different comedians from all over the country, visiting Derby for one night at our venue.</p>

        <p>Our tickets start from just £14 with two tickets for £24! You can also add on food for only an extra £12, view our menu here! Don’t wait around though – tickets sell quickly!</p>

        <p><strong>The evenings schedule:</strong></p>
        <ul>
          <li>5.00pm – Restaurant opens</li>
          <li>7.00pm – Last orders for food</li>
          <li>7.30pm – Time to be seated</li>
          <li>10.00pm – Finish</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Conference Centre<br/>
        Street: London Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE24 8UX
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-comedy-club-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-comedy-club-1</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat>52.9004</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-1.4531</geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derby City Centre Ghost Walk</title>
      <description>
        £15 per person
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p>The now legendary City Centre Walk takes you around Derby City Centre.</p>

        <p>Starting at our meeting point, Guild Hall Clock, Market Place, Derby. We head off to the site of Derby’s first Gaol for stories of witchcraft, execution and treason, then to the Fishmarket to hear the story of the murder of PC Moss the only policeman murdered in Derbyshire, plus Ghost stories of Little Sammy, Viking Skulls, Bonnie Prince Charlie and the Last Pressing to Death in England.</p>

        <p>Walks last approximately 2 hours, starting at 7pm and finishing around 9pm.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby City Centre Ghost Walk<br/>
        Street: Derby Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AH
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-city-centre-ghost-walk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-city-centre-ghost-walk</guid>
      <startDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friar Gate Ghost Walk and Condemned Man's Supper</title>
      <description>
        £29 per person
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3916/8597/5499/Friar_Gate_Ghost_Walk.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Friar Gate Ghost Walk and Condemned Man's Supper"/></p>
        <p>This walk starts and finishes at The Derby Gaol. On your way round you will hear stories of murders, executions, crime, punishment and ghostly occurrences.</p>

        <p>We start with a brief tour of the Gaol, and continue the walk up to Derby’s 3rd and last County Prison on Vernon Gate visiting the execution room and the very haunted tower. We then walk down Agard Street to hear the story of the murder of Eliza Morrow and the last public execution in Derbyshire before returning to our Gaol for a Condemned Man’s Supper.</p>

        <p>Then unlike so many that have been in the Gaol before, you will be permitted to go home!</p>

        <p>Walks last approximately 3 hours, starting at 7pm and finishing around 10pm.</p>

        <p><strong>BAR OPEN FROM 6.30pm</strong></p>

        <p>Entrance to Derby Goal is from Friar Gate side:<br/>
        Underneath 50 - 51 Friar Gate, Derby DE1 1DF.<br/>
        FREE Parking after 6pm</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Gaol<br/>
        Street: 50 Friargate<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 1DF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/friar-gate-ghost-walk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/friar-gate-ghost-walk</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open House at Elvaston Castle</title>
      <description>
        Free (Ground floor entry)
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/6517/3805/3909/Elvaston_Castle_interior_Image_Credit_Elvaston_Castle_and_Gardens_Trust.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Open House at Elvaston Castle"/></p>
        <p>Step inside this historic house for a unique experience and explore its incredible architecture and charm.<br/>
        Bring your family and friends (no dogs inside the castle, please).</p>

        <p>Entry through the Gothic Hall.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Elvaston Castle Country Park<br/>
        Street: Borrowash Road<br/>
        City: Elvaston<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE72 3EP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/open-house-at-elvaston-castle</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/open-house-at-elvaston-castle</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Felicity Hammond: Variations - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3117/3876/6816/Variations_by_Felicity_Hammond.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Felicity Hammond: Variations"/></p>
        <p>Staged in four venues across the UK, Variations by Felicity Hammond is an evolving installation exploring the relationship between geological mining and data mining, image-making and machine learning. V2: Rigged is the second chapter of this project, following V1: Content Aware which was exhibited as a public realm installation as part of the Photoworks Weekender in Brighton, 2024. In Variations, Hammond uses the many landscapes associated with artificial intelligence (AI) to map how digital photographic material makes its journey from mineral to pixel; from the subsurface to the screen. The project aims to reflect on the entanglement of contemporary forms of image making – specifically those made using generative AI tools – with the politics of surveillance, data extraction, and the exploitation of land, resources and labour. Machine learning software relies on an ecosystem that extends far beyond the interfaces its users are presented with.</p>

        <p>Each staging of Variations highlights a distinct aspect of the complex role that machine learning tools play in image-making. V1: Content Aware reflected on the global infrastructure that supports the digital economy, using a shipping container to reveal the contents that are usually hidden. V2: Rigged brings together the extractive processes that exploit the land, humans, and depleting resources. V3: Model Collapse will ask us to consider what happens when the data produced by generative AI is inevitably fed back into its own system, thus polluting its own sense of reality, and V4: Repository will highlight the role of the data storage centre as a site of transmission and as an extractive and polluting process in its own right.</p>

        <p>Staging these installations as four different iterations refers to the variations on the image that generative AI platforms offer its users. When using text to image programmes, we are given four output variations from which to choose. The curatorial process of this project mimics this, where each venue presents a variation on the others that accompany it. Each exhibition is photographically documented and surveilled, the images from which are used as a ‘training set’ for the exhibition that follows it. This process continues for all of the exhibition venues, where the re-staging of each work mimics that of the constantly evolving data sets that inform machine learning platforms. The resulting exhibitions shine a light on the processes and power dynamics at play in a new era of the photographic.</p>

        <p>V2: Rigged – installed at QUAD as part of FORMAT International Photography Festival – exposes how machine learning tools rely on a combination of mineral and data extraction. Crawford (2022) likens artificial intelligence to Lewis Mumford’s concept of the megamachine, where technological processes rely on industrial infrastructures that are kept opaque. This installation seeks to unveil the machine, asking the audience to confront and interact with the aggressive processes that enable machine learning tools to operate. Part camera, part drill head, part processing plant, the machine at the centre of this installation performs the various violent acts of taking (from the brutal processes used to extract rare earth minerals to aggressive surveillance systems and the scraping of personal data) that lie at the centre of computational image-making. Rigs are associated with structures that support both mining and photographic tools; in this exhibition, the rig attempts to bring these processes together.</p>

        <p>The installation includes a pixelated backdrop which depicts a photographic image emerging, in the process of being formed. The machine at the centre of the installation confronts an image of itself against this backdrop, by being placed in front of a mirrored wall. Taking photographs throughout the exhibition, the machine extracts further image data, building on its existing set – images of itself, images of the audience viewing the work, and images of the audience viewing themselves, where the act of looking and taking is central to the machine’s operation. This data will inform V3: Model collapse, the exhibition that follows.</p>

        <p>Woven into the pixilated backdrop are AI generated images that were produced by finding the average image (or in reference to Hito Steyerl’s account of machine learning outputs), the mean image, of the photographic data from the first variation. In these images, men hold hybrid machines; cameras as weapons. The outputs of the machine learning based image generator – produced using the surveillance imagery and documentation of V1 – reveal the violence of the contemporary camera from within its own system. Sontag (1977) explores the analogous connection between camera and gun (we shoot, we aim, we load), and the images generated offer an amalgam of this metaphor, exposing the mechanisms associated with ‘shooting’ in its many forms. However, as Steyerl (2023) suggests, these images are not random hallucinations, they are ‘documentary expressions of society’s views of itself.’ The image is pre-determined, the image is rigged.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/felicity-hammond-variations-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/felicity-hammond-variations-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sujata Setia: A Thousand Cuts - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
        Makings of Past
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4417/3876/7456/Makings_of_Past_artwork_Image_Credit_Artist_Sujata_Setia.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Sujata Setia: A Thousand Cuts"/></p>
        <p>Sujata Setia is the FORMAT25 Award, Lishui Photography Festival Exhibition Award and Genesis Imaging Award winner.</p>

        <p>Derived from the ancient Asian form of torture – “Lingchi”, “A Thousand Cuts” studies patterns of domestic abuse in the South Asian community.</p>

        <p>I have borrowed the metaphorical meaning of Lingchi to showcase the cyclical nature of domestic abuse. The continuous act of chipping at the soul of the abused, is expressed by making cuts on the portrait of the participant. The paper used to print the portrait is a thin A4 sheet, depicting the fragility of her existence.The red colour underneath the portraits signifies not just martyrdom and strength but also the onset of a new beginning.</p>

        <p>I have kept the project at a domestic scale, using resources available within the home as a metaphorical reflection of violence occurring within the human space. The final artwork is photographed in a very closed, tight crop so as to express a sense of suffocation and absence of room for movement.</p>

        <p>My initial intent was to create a metaphorical “waiting room,” where strangers meet and talk to each other without any fear of judgement or hierarchies. An imaginary space where conversations around abusive lived experiences continue to happen. Where it is easy to come out. A room where you are heard, seen, understood and where you feel safe to leave your story behind.</p>

        <p>We started by creating that room as a real space. A space in a church in Hounslow, UK. Many of us met there, several times over. We held hands and spoke at length. No one interjected the other. No one left the room midway.</p>

        <p>I am deeply grateful to the UK-based charity Shewise, which facilitated my connection with the survivors and provided invaluable support by establishing appropriate mental health safeguards. Each survivor who generously agreed to participate in this project is navigating a unique stage of trauma, making it essential for Shewise and me, to ensure that our engagement does not leave their wounds bleeding.</p>

        <p>These initial dialogues led to the creation of a vector of faith between myself and the participants in this project. We then moved on to private one-on-one conversations and me photographing each survivor individually with their consent and their complete control on the way they want to be “seen.” Once I printed the images, the survivor then selected the image she wanted me to start making the cuts on. The motifs made through these cuts are a metaphorical representation of the women’s own lived experiences. Here, I employ the technique of the South Asian art of paper cutting called Sanjhi Art.</p>

        <p>Historically Sanjhi art works were created by the Hindu god Krishna’s female consorts to attract his attention, showcasing an inherent power imbalance between genders. I wanted to create these contemplations of not just abusive lived experiences but also an inquiry into culture.</p>

        <p>Through individual narratives of the survivors we see how coercive control involves regulating the minutiae of everyday life including how women dress and do housework, whom they meet and talk to, and depriving them of or restricting their access to even the most basic necessities of life such as food, water and fresh air.</p>

        <p>Also, through the act of making cuts on the survivor’s portrait, the artist embodies the entangled identities of the abuser and the abused. That helped me understand the perpetrator’s obsession with violence and destruction. There is rhythm in violence. A form of meditation, even.</p>

        <p>This work is an effort to understand abuse from many different frames of references. The role of past in formulating narratives of the present and the future; locating the inter-relativity between childhood and adulthood.</p>

        <p>The long term intention is to bring narratives of abuse into public discourse, arts and human spaces. In that sense, this work is an invitation for an open dialogue that allows both the survivor and society at large, to explore concepts such as trauma, suffering, cultural predispositions, gender and identity politics without sacrificing their own vulnerability or risking confrontation.</p>

        <p>By making physical cuts on the survivor’s portrait, the endeavour is to showcase the juxtaposition of many energies and realms of individual and systemic consciousnesses, in the act of normalising abuse. The focus is on narratives of the South Asian subject. One finds in there, a certain similitude of hegemonic masculinity and a history of colonisation that then helps us sketch out broad patterns that might provide useful lines of inquiry.</p>

        <p>This series also studies the journey of abuse from the private, intimate space where violence occurs; to its place in the public domain, whether it be in terms of how the private reality is subverted; decorated in public or that initial disclosure process when the survivor breaks their silence and speaks out to family, friends, neighbours, colleagues or even absolute strangers. This photographic study draws on interviews with 21 South Asian women (it is an ongoing project) and analyses the interactional and emotional processes of the first public disclosure of their private reality.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sujata-setia-a-thousand-cuts-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sujata-setia-a-thousand-cuts-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lo Lai Lai Natalie: The Days Before The Silent Spring - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
        The Days Before the Silent Spring
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3717/3876/7898/The_Days_Before_the_Silent_Spring_Still_artwork_Artist_Lo_Lai_Lai_Natalie.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="The Days Before The Silent Spring"/></p>
        <p>The Days Before The Silent Spring was a commissioned project supported by WMA Hong Kong from the Hong Kong based artist Lo Lai Lai Natalie. Lai Lai has been engaged in a continuous contemplation of farming practice and ecology, her observations of which are closely-tied to a concern for the social climate in the city of Hong Kong, the vicissitudes and dynamics which transpire between the individual and the collective and the choices which emerge from and contribute to these.</p>

        <p>This multi-channel video installation sees the artist weave together a spectrum of footage shot from different points of view in an homage to the decade-long journey of the farming collective Sangwoodgoon(生活館, literally ”House of Living”), to which she belongs, while reflecting on the multitude of worlds tied together and myriad of life-forms germinated by the practice of farming. Founded in March 2010 amidst the Anti-Hong Kong Express Rail Link (Anti-XRL) and Protect Choi Yuen Village protests, Sangwoodgoon is a group of activists from different walks of life: photographers, designers, art and cultural professionals, educators, journalists, researchers, and writers. Over the years of their farming practice, they have all cultivated a deeper sense of connection and personal relationship with the land, and tasted the pride of new growth—as well as the exhaustion of a harvest. Expanding beyond the writing and observation of crops, flora and fauna, which is a hallmark of her past work, Lai Lai now turns her gaze to her fellow farmers, whose divergent demands, hopes, experiences and struggles are not only testaments to the exhausting nature of negotiations, but also fuel for the collective as a whole.</p>

        <p>In the work, conversations among the members of Sangwoodgoon are interlaced with clips Lai Lai shot in the field throughout the past decade, transforming the busy hubbub of daily life into a rustic polyphony across the field and its universe. From the interaction and fermentation of microorganisms to the various entanglements of flora, fauna, and the farmers, from the dissent and cooperation among group members to the correspondence and democratic cohabitation of communities, these overlapping sounds of the field together form a sonata set to a rhythm of sowing.</p>

        <p>The idea of an impending ‘silent spring’ comes from late marine biologist Rachel Carson’s warning about a forthcoming crisis of species diversity, penned in the 1960s. In her eponymous book, Carson anticipated a gradual erasure of life- forms and sounds caused by pollution from pesticides. And today, in fact, decades of environmental deterioration and global conflicts have brought us to a most appalling present. In this unprecedented chaos we still hear talk of vanishing diversities, lost autonomy, and the danger of silencing. Farmland may seem old and feeble, and the bacteria, species, and communities it nourishes may also feel trivial, but in precarious times their symphony could sound the beginning of a new act.</p>

        <p>A smoky scene prominently features in the film, capturing the ethereal haze that often envelops her farmland in Hong Kong. Farmers burn leftover bones in their pots, meticulously hammering the charred remnants into smaller pieces. Occasionally, they also incinerate waste wood and bamboo sticks, letting the ashes cool before repurposing them as organic fertilizer. The smoke drifts with the wind, creating a subtle outline that gradually dissipates in the lingering mist, embodying the transient nature of life and labor.</p>

        <p>This imagery resonates profoundly with the artist Lo Lai Lai Natalie’s core belief: whether we confront struggle, conflict, social movements, farming, or the experience of diaspora, these challenges serve as mere starting points. They reflect the intricate tapestry of life, where each thread contributes to a larger narrative. In this delicate interplay of existence, Lai Lai emphasizes the importance of authenticity—an unwavering commitment to truth in the face of adversity.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/lo-lai-lai-natalie-the-days-before-the-silent-spring-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/lo-lai-lai-natalie-the-days-before-the-silent-spring-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thero Makepe: We didn’t choose to be born here - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5717/3876/8302/Mama_Mo_Metsi_Artist_Thero_Makepe.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Thero Makepe: We didn’t choose to be born here"/></p>
        <p>Thero Makepe is the British Journal of Photography Award Winner for FORMAT25.</p>

        <p>This body of work is an exploration of Botswana and South Africa’s socio-political fabric through a personal lens. Blending staged portraiture, documentary images and re-enactments, I weave personal family stories with national history.</p>

        <p>These images are part of a photobook that addresses the history of musicality and activism in my family lineage.</p>

        <p>In 1958, my grandfather, Hippolytus Mothopeng, fled South Africa to escape racist Apartheid law. He went to Botswana, a far more peaceful country under British protection that eventually achieved independence in 1966. He worked as a town clerk in Francistown and Gaborone and as a hobbyist jazz musician.</p>

        <p>In contrast, my grandfather’s uncle, Zephaniah Mothopeng, a teacher by profession, became an activist and joined the Pan-African Congress of Azania (PAC), eventually becoming the president of this political party. As a prominent leader of the struggle against Apartheid, my great-uncle Zephania Mothopeng served two separate jail sentences on Robben Island – the latter in 1979 for threatening to overthrow the government – for which he was sentenced to 15 years.</p>

        <p>The title of the project, “We Didn’t Choose to be Born Here”, is a phrase explored in the minds of different family members during crises, separation, and ennui. In my photobook, I also write about my own experiences with activism during the #FeesMustFall protests that took place at the University of Cape Town in 2016, fighting for free, decolonized education across all South African universities.</p>

        <p>My project focuses on the dilemma of personal responsibility in times of crisis. As an individual, do you fight for something greater for yourself in a collective struggle, or do you try to achieve the best for yourself? Furthermore, how does one deal with the reality of the world and personal circumstances they were born into? How does one’s social class influence their ideology and aspirations? I use my family as a conduit to unpack these questions in my book project.</p>

        <p>Growing up in Botswana, I had a very limited and innocent view of my family in South Africa, as I would only see them during holidays and brief visits. I was not aware of their contributions towards the liberation movement in South Africa and the consequences of such, which led to many traumatic experiences.</p>

        <p>My photographic work is collaborative with my family as they share their experiences, stories and memories, and I interpret them as an artist. I do this by either retracing their steps and producing documentary or post-documentary photographs of the places they have been or creating staged re-enactments where different family members, including myself, perform as past family members. I also make portraits of family based on feelings and emotions I want to communicate, such as grief, anxiety and hopelessness. I approach this work not as a singular auteur but as a custodian. Therefore, my family always has a heavy hand in curating themselves as they are photographed and what archival material is left out of this project.</p>

        <p>The contributions of the PAC towards the struggle against Apartheid is greatly underrepresented in South African arts, culture and history. In my personal experience, I only learned of my great-grand uncle’s legacy by innocuously googling my mother’s maiden surname when I was a child and being met with many search results of a revolutionary leader, much to my shock. I view this project as a social responsibility to my family and other Africans. Through this artistic project, I aim to be a custodian of history and knowledge and illuminate the side of radical political action in South Africa that has been greatly suppressed. Although Zephania Mothopeng was my relative, he was also a public figure and, therefore, a ‘collective’ ancestor whose legacy has to be contextualized with sensitivity.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Museum of Making at Derby Silk Mill<br/>
        Street: Silk Mill Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/thero-makepe-we-didnt-choose-to-be-born-here-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/thero-makepe-we-didnt-choose-to-be-born-here-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christopher Gregory-Rivera: EL GOBIERNO TE ODIA (The Government Hates You) - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/2617/3876/9466/San_Juan_Activity_artwork_Artist_Christopher_Gregory-Rivera.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="San Juan Activity"/></p>
        <p>From the 1940’s until 1987 the Puerto Rican Police- in collaboration with the FBI and CIA- watched, intimidated, and in some cases murdered political activists in the Caribbean U.S. Territory. The program remains one of the longest continuous surveillance programs by the US government on its own citizens. Aimed mostly at people advocating for independence from the United States, the operation, led by a secret police division, tracked over 150,000 people and compiled extensive dossiers on over 15,000.</p>

        <p>The program was uncovered in 1987 after a decade-long investigation into the brutal execution of two university students by the Puerto Rico Police Intelligence Division in 1978. When the unit was dismantled, the original surveillance files were returned directly to the victims, whole and unredacted. This is the only such declassification in the world, and a rare view into the inner workings of how states use surveillance for ideological persecution. The files reveal that neighbors, close friends, and even in some cases family members served as informants in exchange for money or under coercion. To this day, those who watched and were watched live side by side in a society with deep wounds but no collective memory of what happened.</p>

        <p>For the last decade Christopher Gregory-Rivera has become a guerrilla archivist, finding these files and rescuing the archive through still life photography, digitization and research. The resulting reconstructed “archive” repairs the web of time where it was broken, affording a window into forbidden political history and a chance at a national truth and reconciliation process at a time when the colonial relationship with the US is more fraught than ever.</p>

        <p>The body of work appropriates material from the photographic archive of the secret police in the National Archives of Puerto Rico which contains over 40,000 images. A part of those images were digitized by the artists and submitted digitally back to the archive in an effort to protect the vulnerable archive against the entropy of the tropics and increasingly aggressive budget restrictions at the archive. The work also draws from the hundreds of victims that still have files in their possession as well as all of the surveillance files unable to be returned and administrative documents of the police.</p>

        <p>The appropriated images are enigmatic. Some images were taken hidden but most were confrontational, obvious; the panopticon materialized in daily life. In the images there are moments where somebody looks directly back at the camera: an interaction, a collaboration or rejection. The stares are glimpses into the perception, attitude and awareness of this opaque, secret, illegal practice by its own subjects and sometimes the perpetrators. If the images the police took of themselves were meant to be secret, staring into the camera is its acknowledgement. If the images the secret police took of subjects are violent, the counter gaze is its resistance.</p>

        <p>The Intelligence Division created an archive that was intended as a weapon against those who governments see as a threat to their political project. The images are largely devoid of captions and present more questions than they answer. They are heartbreakingly ambiguous given that they are one of the only documents of this largely forbidden and forgotten political history.</p>

        <p>The original photographs by the artist examine the physical objects and bureaucratic detritus of the massive secret surveillance program. Each file was painstakingly assembled and carbon copied by hand. The vicious and absurd scale with which information was collected leads us to believe that it was the practice of watching itself that was more important that the information collected, especially since it was collected illegally and not admissible in court. The evidenciary nature of the still lives reinforces that it is the volume, scale and craft of the file that is important, not what it contains. Not dissimilar to how police photographers surveilled visually; the artist surveils the objects back inviting viewers to make up their own narratives about the content.</p>

        <p>Although the secret police has been disbanded this practice has not ended. The most recent component of the work are stills from a leaked police video documenting protests in 2017 against the imposition of a Federal Fiscal Control Board. In subsequent investigations into the wrongful arrests of protestors, it came to light that not only were there troves of footage but also a huge cache of personal data and private conversations requested from Facebook of over 500 individuals who interacted with protest videos. Although deeply rooted in the history of Puerto Rico, the project’s goal is to offer a glimpse into the tactics that threaten true and free civil discourse to this day around the globe.</p>

        <p>Gregory-Rivera’s images ask: by understanding the state’s gaze can we come to understand the current civil society it built? If so, does that allow us to dismantle its control over us now?</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Christopher Gregory-Rivera: EL GOBIERNO TE ODIA (The Government Hates You) - Part of FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: 19 Chapel Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3GU
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/christopher-gregory-rivera-el-gobierno-te-odia-the-government-hates-you-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/christopher-gregory-rivera-el-gobierno-te-odia-the-government-hates-you-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Garrett: Teeth of the Wolf - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
        Award artwork
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7817/3877/0040/Award_artwork_Artist_Jenna_Garrett.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Jenna Garrett: Teeth of the Wolf"/></p>
        <p>Jenna Garrett is the Spectrum Imaging Award winner for FORMAT25.</p>

        <p>At 11:16 pm on January 6, 2021, Proud Boys leader Enrique Tarrio posted a video of himself standing in front of the United States Capitol. It was taken days before his group—along with hundreds of other dissidents—violently stormed the building to halt the ratification of the presidential election. Tarrio’s face is shrouded by a gruesome mask, a cape flowing behind him. And I couldn’t stop thinking I’d seen such a mask before—in a relatively unknown 19th-century photo taken near my hometown.</p>

        <p>The mask—black and horned—belonged to the Bald Knobbers, a vigilante group that sprung up in the Ozark Mountains in the aftermath of the Civil War. They were everyday citizens—shop owners, ministers, sheriffs—who swore to protect their community from lawlessness. In just five years, their numbers swelled from 13 to an estimated 500. By the time they disbanded, 17 people were killed, plus countless reports of floggings, arson, jail escapes, and lynchings. The Bald Knobbers became the terror they swore to defeat.</p>

        <p>My project Teeth of the Wolf (2019-present) interrogates the story of these men. It’s a history obfuscated by secrecy and whitewashed through decades of mythology and commercialization. Drawing from the few remaining documents and photo archives, I reimagine the violence of the past and recontextualize its incarnation in the present.</p>

        <p>A vigilante is broadly defined as “a self-appointed doer of justice.” The Bald Knobbers are an obscure part of a sweeping American legacy, one that uses intimidation and violence to maintain power perceived to be under threat. Today, this spirit manifests as rogue border militias, local paramilitary groups, and organizations like the Proud Boys. They are mostly white men, driven by secrecy, grievance, and a belief they have the right to step in as the true authority when the government fails them.</p>

        <p>Teeth of the Wolf drags these machinations into the light, examining it not as an anomaly, but a cyclical part of my nation’s history. The work includes archival imagery, locations and people connected with significant events, and contemporary depictions in local culture. The goal is to extend the Bald Knobbers’ legacy beyond its origins, revealing how their tactics haven’t disappeared, but merely mutated.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Jenna Garrett: Teeth of the Wolf - Part of FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: 19 Chapel Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3GU
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/jenna-garrett-teeth-of-the-wolf-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/jenna-garrett-teeth-of-the-wolf-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Blakemore: Earthly Delights - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4417/3883/4083/1970_John_Blakemore.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="John Blakemore: Earthly Delights"/></p>
        <p>“Inspiration is a myth. Just go and play.”</p>

        <p>These were the words John Blakemore would divine upon conflicted students whilst lecturing at the University of Derby.</p>

        <p>Widely regarded as a master of darkroom photography, John Blakemore is celebrated for the richness and textures that he creates within his prints. Using a technical harmony of the 5×4 film medium, the Zone System and an incredible mastery of the darkroom printing process, he creates a signature tonal richness and opulence within his photography worthy of the title.</p>

        <p>Using nature as his muse, John captures landscapes inspired by texture and space that can be appreciated by audiences regardless of their knowledge of the skill behind the printing. Rustling silver birch trees and the movement of water are halted and brought to the eye of the viewer in a seeming instant.</p>

        <p>A calm is created in John’s prints in which time feels torn between endlessness and standstill- it’s the microsecond before the intake of breath as the viewer notices the beauty of a petal, rock pool, fern or other aspects of nature that can elude us all too easily. We are invited to experience this moment that he has discovered… before, we presume, the moment ends and continues beyond our solitary experience- the birdsong picked back up beyond the lens, the water bubbles slithered by and the fern fronds once again twitched in the breeze. John stated on the process of his landscapes:</p>

        <p>“To be alone in the landscape can be an intense and moving experience. At times one feels a oneness with nature; at other times the landscape feels hostile.”</p>

        <p>A description similar to his experience of the darkroom, a place of both wonders and intensity for all who experienced it:</p>

        <p>“I always loved the darkroom: the isolation, the cloistered quiet, the dim ambience and the muted sound of running water.”</p>

        <p>John would share this magic when teaching students, who with him would discover the still and fervent moment in the darkroom where an image started to appear as the paper swirled around the developing chemical, the dash to dodge or burn the print as light passed through the negative- the held breath as they brought their prints out into the light for the first time.</p>

        <p>At a time where the conflict between analogue and digital photography seemed to be going in digital’s favour, he effortlessly showed the wonder of darkroom printing. Trancelike, assured, attentive, he would move around the darkroom to produce prints of such quality as to appear like velvet on the page… before later going on to tear them up. A practice to prevent unknown sales of his works, understandable but horrifying to witness as a student all the same. The conflict of creation and destruction was something to come to terms within the darkroom, a place where negatives and prints often wouldn’t turn out the way anticipated.</p>

        <p>Similarly, when the landscapes John captured began to change due to human damage and interference, he turned to natural items brought in from his garden, creating the iconic Tulips still life series.</p>

        <p>John described the tulip as a “flower of constant metamorphosis”, becoming for him an ‘object of attention and fascination’ for many years to come. Capturing life, death, generations and mutations of tulips, his photographs were a result of meditation, care and consideration of the flower that had caught his inspiration.</p>

        <p>In 2024, Derby Museums accessioned 12 photographic prints of John’s into the collection of the city he had called home for over 50 years, bringing together prints from a range of projects including his iconic tulips and his Derbyshire and Wales landscapes. This new collection brings together a life’s dedication to technical skill, analogue practice and celebrating the natural world around us.</p>

        <p>It encourages us once more to witness that age old conflict between the decisive moment of the photograph and the flowing of time. It asks us to rediscover the joy of the thoughtful and meditative processes of analogue at a time where digital is monarch. Most of all, it is a swansong to the brilliance of John Blakemore, a man of endless inspiration, wit and skill.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Museum of Making at Derby Silk Mill<br/>
        Street: Silk Mill Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/john-blakemore-earthly-delights-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/john-blakemore-earthly-delights-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W. W. Winter: Behind the Barbed Wire - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8517/3883/6488/German_officers_POW_Playing_Chess_WW1_courtesy_of_the_W._W._Winters_archive.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Behind the Barbed Wire"/></p>
        <p>Behind the Barbed WireDuring the Great War of 1914-1918, W. W. Winter were commissioned to photograph German officer prisoners interned in camps near Derby, at Donington Hall and Kegworth. Only 54 of the many photographs taken have survived the intervening years.</p>

        <p>Although the establishment, operation and eventual closure of the camps is not a new topic of study, original material was discovered and included, along with glass plates found in a box at the Winter’s studio.</p>

        <p>The images go some way to illustrate a remarkable and largely unknown story which has been revealed only after much painstaking research.The photographs were created to enable prisoners to reach out to the world ‘beyond the barbed wire’ and they therefore form an important part of the study of the psychological aspects of imprisonment.</p>

        <p>The discovery led to the creation of this exhibition, which was first shown in 2019, to commemorate a century since the end of the FirstWorld War. It has been bought together for FORMAT 2025 to enable it to be viewed again within the context of CONFLICTED.The complete collection is reproduced in a book to accompany this exhibition. It highlights the unique lifestyle of these privileged officers, alongside stores of escapes, the catastrophic flu epidemic of 1918 and politics at the highest level.</p>

        <p>The principle and more exciting outcome has been the gradual awareness of the true significance of the images. They have been analysed not merely as artefacts to elicit the identity of the subjects, but as artistic creations in their own right.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: W. W. Winter: Behind the Barbed Wire - Part of FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: 19 Chapel Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3GU
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/w-w-winter-behind-the-barbed-wire-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/w-w-winter-behind-the-barbed-wire-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alicia Bruce: The Greatest 36 Holes? - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/9017/3883/7194/The_Greatest_36_Holes_Alicia_Bruce.png?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="The Greatest 36 Holes?"/></p>
        <p>“It needs to be remembered by all that we do not inherit this earth from our ancestors; we borrow it from our descendants.”—David Milne, Menie resident, Aberdeenshire, 2010</p>

        <p>In 2006, Donald Trump announced plans to build “The Greatest Golf Course in the World” on Aberdeenshire’s dynamic coastline, an area designated as a Site of Special Scientific Interest (SSSI) for its ecological significance and natural beauty. The development, approved in 2008 by the Scottish government under First Minister Alex Salmond, prioritized promised economic benefits over environmental concerns. The decision sparked controversy, with campaigners arguing that the impact on the dunes, wildlife, and local residents was too high a price to pay.</p>

        <p>For photographer Alicia Bruce, the Menie dunes held personal significance. She grew up nearby and played on them as a child. The dramatic transformation of this cherished landscape into a golf course motivated Bruce to begin documenting Trump’s development in Menie. Since then, she has created an ongoing body of work that spans nearly two decades, a record of the ecological and social changes brought by Trump’s ventures in the region. Her project covers not only the construction of Trump’s first golf course but also the second course, which began in 2023 and threatens the remaining sand dunes, stretching all the way to Balmedie Country Park.</p>

        <p>The alterations to the landscape have been significant: sand dunes have been stabilized, shifted, and sprayed with hydroseed, altering their natural state. Once open to the public, much of the land is now fenced off, with access denied by Trump security personnel who claim to be “protecting the dunes.” The Menie Coastguard Cottages, home to long-time residents, have been emptied, with tenants dislodged to make way for further development. Bruce’s latest images made in 2024 capture this ongoing transformation, juxtaposing the site’s altered state with its former natural beauty as Trump builds a second golf course.</p>

        <p>This new project phase builds on Bruce’s critically acclaimed monograph, I Burn But I Am Not Consumed (Daylight Books, 2023), which documented 16 years of Trump’s impact on the Menie community. Her work highlights the resilience and humanity of local residents who have endured years of disruption, even as they were publicly dismissed and derided by Trump, who famously labelled them “peasants” and “pigs.” Bruce’s images not only tell a story of environmental loss but also reflect on themes of human and land rights, displacement, and resistance.</p>

        <p>Recognized for its cultural significance, Bruce’s work was celebrated in a 2013 Scottish Parliamentary motion, and her photographs have been exhibited internationally, including at MoCP Chicago and the Lishui Photography Culture Center. These images have shifted public perception of Menie’s residents, presenting them not as obstacles to progress but as individuals fighting for their homes and heritage.</p>

        <p>Deeply personal and political, Bruce’s ongoing documentation of Trump’s developments in Menie serves as a humane and poignant portrait of a community in conflict. It offers a critical reflection on the lasting impacts of a development marketed as “The Greatest Golf Course in the World” and the consequences of prioritizing profit over preservation.</p>

        <p>Film and processing for the 2024 project phase was made possible with the Richard and Siobhan Coward Foundation Grant for Analogue Photography.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Electric Daisy<br/>
        Street: 1 - 4 Bold Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3NT
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/alicia-bruce-the-greatest-36-holes-coming-soon-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/alicia-bruce-the-greatest-36-holes-coming-soon-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Ormerod - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5817/3883/8205/Michael_Ormerod_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Michael Ormerod"/></p>
        <p>Michael Ormerod (1947-1991) was a British photographer with a distinctive and powerful voice, whose career was tragically cut short on August 7th 1991 in a road accident on his last field trip to the USA. He is known for striking and evocative images capturing American landscapes and urban scenes. His work often depicted the raw, gritty reality of life in America, showcasing both its beauty and its challenges.</p>

        <p>Born in Hyde in Cheshire in 1947, Ormerod studied economics at Hull University, before going on to study photography at Trent Polytechnic. He ran a freelance photography business in Staffordshire for many years and taught photography at Newcastle College. He spent many of his Summers from the mid-70s to 1991 travelling in a camper van across America. Fascinated by the American image, and following in the footsteps of Robert Frank, Ormerod took to the American West to find a washed out dream of capitalism. His images capture a strange juxtaposition of an American beauty tainted by a hidden sense of menace and corruption.</p>

        <p>The photographs are understated, but show an unseen America, where the industrial heartland is decaying, highways stand empty and towns are deserted. The subjects of Ormerod’s work are the disenfranchised. A teenager cycles through her neighbourhood wearing a Halloween-style hockey mask, a Native American man stands in a graveyard, their expressions are unreadable.</p>

        <p>The work subverts traditional American icons. A white picket fence is staved in, a huge billboard for Miss Teen Dakota USA stands next to an empty highway. Inverting the famous Hollywood sign, Ormerod photographs a Texaco sign from the back, dominating the empty, Western landscape. The works also show humour – a giant fake dinosaur looms in the distance of a desert landscape, a stuffed moose head is displayed in the window of a diner. The subjects of the work are unconventional, surreal and sometimes mundane, but create an atmosphere of an eerie backwater America.</p>

        <p>His photographs are those of the outsider, constantly travelling through a no-man’s-land. A sense of pessimism pervades, showing how the commercial boom of the 1950s has collapsed, leaving deserted streets, rubbish dumps and alienation. It is a land where the American Dream has turned sour.</p>

        <p>After his untimely death in 1991, and with the support of Ormerod’s parents, friends and colleagues, a book, States of America, was published as a lasting testament to his distinctive and compelling vision. An accompanying exhibition was held at the Zelda Cheatle Gallery in London in 1993.</p>

        <p>Ormerod’s photography gained recognition for its powerful storytelling and unique perspective on the American experience. His legacy continues to influence contemporary photographers, and his work remains highly regarded in the photography community. Despite this, over the last 33 years, only two major exhibitions of his work have taken place at the Sheffield Graves Art Gallery in 2003, and at the Crane Kalman Brighton Gallery as part of the Brighton Photo Biennial in 2010.</p>

        <p>Since his death, Ormerod’s body of work has been held at the Millennium Picture Library in London. At a family event in 2012, celebrating his life and photographic work, his daughter Ali had a conversation with one of Ormerod’s closest friends and fellow photographer Geoff Weston. This conversation led to a shared intention: to go back to the archive and revisit his photographic legacy. There they discovered a trove of previously unseen negatives from Ormerod’s trips to America. Working closely with the help of Alan Thoburn, over the course of a decade, these previously unseen images have been curated into a new collection deserving of public display. At the end of 2024, a new book, American Landscapes, was published by RRB Photobooks featuring over 50 of these never-before-seen works and an exhibition was held in London to coincide with this release.</p>

        <p>The work has received much public and critical acclaim and created a surge of renewed interest in this wonderful, overlooked photographer’s work. A reappraisal of his powerful and uncompromising chronicle of America is long overdue.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Michael Ormerod - Part of FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: University of Derby, Markeaton Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE22 3AW
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/michael-ormerod-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/michael-ormerod-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OUR RIUKZAK: Maria + Yehor - FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1817/3883/9305/Artem_Humilevskyi_Image_Credit_OUR_RIUKZAK_Maria__plus__Yehor.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="OUR RIUKZAK: Maria + Yehor"/></p>
        <p>OUR RIUKZAK is an invitation to hold time in your hands, to unfold its layers, and to confront its haunting echoes. This portable exhibition-in-a-box collapses nearly a century of history, bringing the stories of Ukraine’s Holodomor famine-genocide (1932-1933) into dialogue with the ongoing atrocities of today’s war. It bridges memory, trauma, and resilience, urging us to witness the lives of children caught in the violence of history.</p>

        <p>At its heart, OUR RIUKZAK is a bilingual (Ukrainian English) photographic exhibition, designed to foster reflection and dialogue in intimate, adaptable spaces. The box—compact and unassuming when closed—unfolds to reveal a cross-shaped display containing 24 posters, descriptive labels, and three essays. The form echoes its contents: a physical manifestation of stories unfolding, inviting us to trace the connections between historical and contemporary crises.</p>

        <p>The essays, including one by Dr. Kristina Hook, ground the project in a critical framework, linking past genocides to contemporary realities. Hook’s analysis highlights how the Holodomor’s legacy has shaped Ukraine’s cultural resilience and how historical narratives are weaponized by authoritarian regimes. These essays offer context, helping audiences to navigate the images, the silences, and the emotions embedded in this exhibition. They emphasize that resilience is not a passive state—it is an act of resistance, a force that endures even in the face of erasure.</p>

        <p>At the core of OUR RIUKZAK lies a focus on children. It asks us to reflect on the vulnerability of those who often bear the heaviest burdens of conflict. Children are both witnesses and victims, their lives profoundly shaped by trauma yet embodying a resilience that defies the weight of violence. Through a delicate interplay of historical gravitas and contemporary urgency, the project creates a continuum of memory—one that challenges us to see the threads connecting past and present.</p>

        <p>The Holodomor section features works from Lesia Maruschak’s Project MARIA and Roman Pyatkovka’s Holodomor: Phantoms of the 1930s. Maruschak’s imagery is inspired by Maria F., a young survivor of the Holodomor who emigrated to Canada. Her work captures the silence of intergenerational trauma—the gaps in memory that persist and the resilience that sustains. It is a meditation on absence and on the persistence of memory even when voices are silenced. Pyatkovka’s work shifts the lens to individual tragedies under the Soviet regime: children coerced into betrayal, families torn apart, and lives fractured by systemic violence. His photographs confront us with the invisible scars of fear and oppression, reminding us how power shapes the most intimate corners of human life.</p>

        <p>The contemporary section transitions to the war in Ukraine today, focusing on the resilience of children living through unimaginable realities.</p>

        <p>Named after Yehor, an 11-year-old boy whose life was chronicled by Lynsey Addario in The New York Times Magazine, this section includes photographs by Ukrainian visual artists and photojournalists such as Pulitzer Prize-winner Evgeny Maloletka. These images illuminate the children’s resilience in the face of unimaginable hardship, capturing not only the physical destruction of war but also the emotional landscapes of young lives shaped by displacement, violence, and survival. Their defiant spirits, framed within the fragility of childhood, act as a powerful metaphor for the enduring courage of a nation’s youngest citizens.</p>

        <p>What makes OUR RIUKZAK truly transformative is its participatory design. As the box is unpacked and installed in museums, libraries, schools, and community spaces, audiences become curators of their own experience. This act of unfolding and arranging emphasizes that memory is not static. It evolves as we engage with it, as we question and reinterpret the narratives we inherit. The inclusion of children’s voices deepens this engagement, asking participants to consider the psychological dimensions of conflict and the ethical responsibilities of witnessing.</p>

        <p>The pairing of Maria’s story with Yehor’s illuminates the unbroken thread of trauma and resilience that weaves through Ukrainian history. It is a juxtaposition that demands reflection: How do we hold the past while confronting the present? How do we translate memory into action? The act of remembering becomes an active form of resistance, a way to push back against forces that seek to erase.</p>

        <p>Ultimately, OUR RIUKZAK is more than an exhibition—it is an urgent call to empathy. It asks us to sit with discomfort, to confront the weight of loss, and to honor the strength of those who endure. It reminds us that children are not just symbols of innocence—they are agents of survival and resilience, their stories shaping our collective understanding of conflict and humanity. By engaging with OUR RIUKZAK, we are not merely looking at history; we are invited to feel its echoes, to hold its weight, and to carry its lessons forward. It is a space for mourning and for hope, for reckoning and for action.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: OUR RIUKZAK: Maria + Yehor - FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: University of Derby, Markeaton Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE22 3AW
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/our-riukzak-maria-plus-yehor-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/our-riukzak-maria-plus-yehor-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lishui / FORMAT Photography Festival Award: Island Ferry by Xu Jun - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/9017/3884/0308/By_Xu_Ju.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Island Ferry by Xu Jun"/></p>
        <p>Floods occurred in the Bingshen year of Yongle in the Ming Dynasty (1416), and the Wu family’s house in Huitan Village, Lanxi County, was destroyed. After the severe famine, Wu Yuanfu Gong moved to live on a sandbank built up from the waste beach. After that, other surnames moved in one after another. This is where Zhoushang Village, Xiangxi Town, Lanxi City comes from. The civilization has been passed down for 608 years. The two villages of Zhoushang and Huitan, which share the same surname as Wu, have been traveling by small boat for more than 300 years.</p>

        <p>The Huanghuang Dam was completed in the 59th year of Emperor Kangxi’s reign (1720), which changed the shape of the ancient river course of Lanxi. Under the pattern of “Shigu Mountain three hundred years ago, Huangwantan three hundred years later”, the Xiangxi section of the Daxi River From Xiangxi Wharf, it was moved westward for a kilometer to the west of the village to form a boundary. Xiangtou Pier 16 has also been moved to the island. However, the boats on the island are like forests, and merchants are busy. The village on Zhoushang is like a city. It has prospered and was once the seat of the Zhoushang District Government and District Office.</p>

        <p>I was born in Xiangxi Village, a thousand meters away from Zhoushang Village. When I was 6 years old, my aunt pointed to a piece of land next to Lijiang Pit at Zhoushang Dam and said, “These fields have been given to our family. From now on, we will grow our crops in this way.” “From this, I have the cultural elements of Zhoushang Village in my heart. The most unforgettable thing is the first time I took a passenger ship in 1980. Because my mother was an educated youth, she was promoted to work in the county cotton textile factory. Carrying big bags and small bags, my father and I followed my mother to Zhoushang Pier and boarded the largest ship on the Lanjiang River. Passenger steamers come into town. After that, I sometimes walked to Chaushang Pier to take pictures of the docks and boats.</p>

        <p>In the new era of common prosperity, Zhoushang Village still has a unique brilliance beside the Lanjiang River. At the end of 2022, the Xiangnu Highway Bridge from Zhoushang to Huitan will break ground. This rainbow will firmly tie the family, friendship and love on both sides of the Taiwan Strait. I am happy and eager. On the eve of the ferry being replaced by a bridge, I raised my camera to freeze the village scenery and culture; to freeze the surging waves, surfing ferries, riverside piers and ferry culture, on the prosperity of the motherland, Add colorful flowers.</p>

        <p>On the island, on the boat, how many winds and rains, how many springs and autumns, how many traces are left, all are remembered with this set of pictures, remember! Remember nostalgia.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Lishui / FORMAT Photography Festival Award: Island Ferry by Xu Jun - Part of FORMAT25<br/>
        Street: 19 Chapel Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3GU
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/lishui-format-photography-festival-award-island-ferry-by-xu-jun-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/lishui-format-photography-festival-award-island-ferry-by-xu-jun-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fernanda: le foto ritrovate: Undiscovered photos of Italian rural life (1930-1950) - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/6617/3884/1044/Fernanda_le_foto_ritrovate_Undiscovered_photos_of_Italian_rural_life.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Fernanda: le foto ritrovate"/></p>
        <p>One of the greatest acts of civil resistance during the Second World War was the courageous actions of the lowliest in Italian society – the contadini (sharecroppers) – who, after the signing of an Armistice between Italy and the Allies in September 1943 and at great risk to themselves sheltered up to 25,000 Allied soldiers who had escaped en masse from PoW camps the length and breadth of the country.</p>

        <p>The accidental discovery of this photographic collection hidden in a drawer has brought to light a valuable archive documenting and describing rural life in the typical hillside villages of Le Marche region, in Italy, specifically during the years surrounding the Second World War. These images provide a strikingly neorealist snapshot, echoing the movement that emerged in Italy during the same period, championed by photographers such as Mario De Biasi, Arturo Zavattini, Franco Pinna, Chiara Samugheo, Nino Migliori, and others.</p>

        <p>The original collection comprises 150 Ferrania negatives stored in three cases, discovered in 2019 in the home of Ms. Fernanda Millevolte after her passing. The negatives appeared to have aged remarkably well, and further research revealed they had never been printed. The photographs exhibit a degree of amateurism, suggesting the camera was in the hands of someone with little technical experience, likely attempting to emulate the composition techniques of professional photographers. However, it is precisely this amateur quality that gives the collection its extraordinary documentary value. The unpolished style captures raw, unfiltered scenes of everyday life, offering a genuine glimpse into the historical period.</p>

        <p>Despite extensive research, it was initially impossible to identify either the photographer or the subjects depicted in the photographs. The images were exhibited in Le Marche region on two occasions, in 2019 and 2024, in the area where they were presumably taken, near the hometown of Ms. Fernanda Millevolte, with the purpose of identifying the individuals portrayed. This effort led to the recognition of approximately half of the people featured in the photographs, but the photographer remains unknown.</p>

        <p>Curated by Giordano Viozzi and Valentina Cicarilli of the “Associazione La Casa della Memoria” in collaboration with the Monte San Martino Trust, this exhibition for Format Festival highlights not only the significance of these photographs but also the contadini’s quiet heroism. For over twenty years, both organizations have been conducting historical research on Civil Resistance working tirelessly to commemorate these acts of heroism in support of the Allies and to bring stories of civil resistance to light. The bonds forged during wartime between the contadini and Allied soldiers, and the bravery of those who risked their lives to protect strangers, inspired the formation of the Monte San Martino Trust. This collection places the contadini and their subsistence lifestyle at the center of the narrative, illustrating how their courage and resilience became symbols of humanity and solidarity during one of history’s darkest times.</p>

        <p>Text by Giordano Viozzi and Valentina Cicarilli for Associazione La Casadella Memoria di Servigliano and Anne Copley for Monte San Martino Trust.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: The Smallprint Company<br/>
        Street: Friary Villas, 2-3 Friary Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 1JF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/fernanda-le-foto-ritrovate-undiscovered-photos-of-italian-rural-life-1930-1950-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/fernanda-le-foto-ritrovate-undiscovered-photos-of-italian-rural-life-1930-1950-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young FORMAT Open Call - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1617/3884/4120/Yuxi_Hao_Dad_in_Tiananmen_square_from_Those_who_leave_Those_who_stay_2024.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Young FORMAT Open Call"/></p>
        <p>YOUNG FORMAT Open Call is an exhibition opportunity for young photographers, UK-based, aged 25 years and under.</p>

        <p>The FORMAT curatorial team would like to work with photographs of children and young people, aged 25 years and under, to exhibit as part of the FORMAT25 Biennale.</p>

        <p>This year’s festival is exploring ‘CONFLICTED’ and it will feature a range of work by photographers from all around the world. It’s a brilliant opportunity to show young photographic skills to a huge audience of photography fans from far and wide.</p>

        <p>Submissions came from different backgrounds, and age groups all around the country to look at FORMAT25’s theme, ‘CONFLICTED’. Featuring different angles and viewpoints, experimenting with new techniques and exploring unconventional pictures and methods, the exhibition celebrates the imagination and creativity of young people through the medium of photography.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-open-call-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-open-call-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young FORMAT: Schools in Residence: Horizons Sixth Form - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7317/3885/1562/Young_FORMAT_Schools_in_Residence_Horizons_Sixth_Form.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Young FORMAT: Schools in Residence"/></p>
        <p>Funded by the Paul Hamlyn Foundation, QUAD’s Schools in Residence programme enables pupils in formal education settings in Derby, particularly those experiencing systemic inequality or disadvantage, to thrive through participating in creative workshops.</p>

        <p>Artists and photographers joined the schools and delivered sessions for children and young people ages 8-18 at Pear Tree Community Junior School, St Martins School & Horizons Sixth Form and Derby Moor Academy. Students explored the theme of Conflict using traditional and digital photography and mixed media techniques.</p>

        <p><strong>Horizons Sixth Form</strong><br/>
        <em>Who We Are by Karen Logan</em><br/>
        Led by artist Karen Logan, Who We Are is a collection of mixed media collages created by students from Horizons 6th Form, who meet with QUAD each Tuesday for weekly workshops. Taking inspiration from collage artist Maria Rivans, the students discussed how her images can often depict an individual in the centre with all their thoughts, interests and memories surrounding them, like projections from their mind. Using DSLR cameras, iPads and camera phones, the students captured objects of interest in Derby Museums and from around the city and used these images to explore photo montage techniques with stylised self-portraiture.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-schools-in-residence-horizons-sixth-form-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-schools-in-residence-horizons-sixth-form-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young FORMAT: Schools in Residence: Derby Moor Academy - Part of FORMAT25</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7917/3885/2100/Young_FORMAT_Schools_in_Residence_Derby_Moor_Academy.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Young FORMAT: Schools in Residence Derby Moor Academy"/></p>
        <p>Funded by the Paul Hamlyn Foundation, QUAD’s Schools in Residence programme enables pupils in formal education settings in Derby, particularly those experiencing systemic inequality or disadvantage, to thrive through participating in creative workshops. Artists and photographers joined the schools and delivered sessions for children and young people ages 8-18 at Pear Tree Community Junior School, St Martins School & Horizons Sixth Form and Derby Moor Academy. Students explored the theme of Conflict using traditional and digital photography and mixed media techniques.</p>

        <p><strong>Derby Moor Academy</strong><br/>
        <em>DM Lens Lab by Jon Legge</em></p>

        <p>DM Lens Lab was created by 24 Year 10 Art students with photographer Jon Legge. During weekly workshops, students learned about technical processes of the DSLR cameras and gained photographic skills. Students gained an understanding of how the approach of the photographer changes the meaning of the image. They were then encouraged to explore their own ideas through task driven experimentation in and around their school surroundings.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-schools-in-residence-derby-moor-academy-part-of-format25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/young-format-schools-in-residence-derby-moor-academy-part-of-format25</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just the Tonic Comedy Club</title>
      <description>
        Just the Tonic logo
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5817/4040/7860/Just_te_Tonic_logo.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Just the Tonic Comedy Club"/></p>
        <p>Come and join us for a new monthly Thursday night at Electric Daisy, we will be bringing you some of the best comedians in comedy at an affordable price once a month. Come along and support the venue and Live comedy.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Electric Daisy<br/>
        Street: 1 - 4 Bold Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3NT
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/just-the-tonic-comedy-club-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/just-the-tonic-comedy-club-1</guid>
      <startDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 19:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derby Riverboat Trips</title>
      <description>
        Adults £8 | Under 16s £6 | Family £22 | Under 3s Free (ticket still required)
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5817/1808/8792/Derby_Riverboat_2.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Derby Riverboat Trips"/></p>
        <p>Eco-Friendly River Cruises return from 5 April 2025!</p>

        <p>Hop aboard Outram, Derby’s solar-powered electric boat, for a relaxing 45-minute return cruise from Causey Bridge to Darley Abbey. Glide through Darley Park and Chester Green along one of the UK’s most biodiverse urban rivers.</p>

        <p>With a mix of indoor and outdoor seating, onboard café and sustainable gift shop, the experience is both comfortable and eco-conscious. Children can enjoy interactive STEM demos, activity packs and toys.</p>

        <p>An engaging audio commentary by Sir David Suchet brings the river’s rich history to life.</p>

        <p>Departs from temporary Causey Bridge platform (opposite the Museum of Making)<br/>
        Please arrive 10 mins before departure<br/>
        Accessibility: Temporary access only via ladder until permanent platform installed</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Museum of Making at Derby Silk Mill<br/>
        Street: Silk Mill Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-riverboat-trips</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-riverboat-trips</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 12:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:45:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bike Night - monthly</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4217/4411/3866/Beige_And_Red_Illustrative_Bike_Trip_Promotion_Instagram_Story_1080_x_1350_px.jpg-20250408130321.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Bike Night - monthly"/></p>
        <p>2nd and 4th Tuesday of every month we will be holding our Bike Meets. Bikes, trikes and unicycles all welcome!</p>

        <p>We have listened to your feedback so we’re lighting up the BBQ and serving burgers and hot dogs, with drinks served from the Tramshed cafe!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Great Northern Classics<br/>
        Street: 274 – 278 Osmaston Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE24 8AE
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bike-night-monthly</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bike-night-monthly</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live Music at BEAR Iron Gate</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1516/8199/5437/bearirongate3.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Live Music at BEAR Iron Gate"/></p>
        <p>🎶 Live Music at BEAR Iron Gate 🎶<br/>
        Good vibes. Great drinks. Even better tunes.</p>

        <p>Join us on the last Saturday of every month for live music at BEAR Iron Gate, the perfect excuse for a night of cocktails, small plates, and toe-tapping tunes.</p>

        <p>✨ Music kicks off from 7PM<br/>
        🍸 Cocktails 2 for £16<br/>
        🍽️ Small Plates 3 for £18<br/>
        Mark your calendars, book your table and we'll see you there!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: BEAR Derby Irongate<br/>
        Street: 7 Iron Gate<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3FJ
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/live-music-at-bear-iron-gate</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/live-music-at-bear-iron-gate</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cult Film Club</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/6217/0176/8188/Cult_Film_Club_Event_Artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Cult Film Club"/></p>
        <p>Cult Film Club is QUAD’s bi-monthly cinematic journey through infamous cult films and hidden gems spanning all genres. Hosted by Johann Chipol of the Enigmatic Retro Rewind YouTube Channel, the screening embraces the weird, wonderful, and downright quirky with deep dive introductions, encouraged audience interaction and a mini quiz at every screening. The Cult Film Club is where fun meets film, and the extraordinary becomes the norm.</p>

        <p>Join the Cult Film Club Facebook Group to keep up to date with the latest screenings and Subscribe to Enigmatic Retro Rewind on Youtube for videos and podcasts on all things cult and nostalgic.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/cult-film-club</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/cult-film-club</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dracula Returns To Derby – 101 years and Counting</title>
      <description>
        FREE – Give What You Think.
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/9117/4652/5976/Dracula_in_fornt_of_the_Old_Bell_Hotel_Derby.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Dracula Returns To Derby – 101 years and Counting"/></p>
        <p>On May 15th 1924, the World premier of Dracula took place at The Grand Theatre on Babington Lane, Derby.<br/>
        Produced by Hamilton Deane, this adaptation of Bram Stoker’s Dracula became the blueprint for The Count as we know them today, a character portrayed by Bela Lugosi, Christopher Lee, and a wealth of performers across stage and screen.</p>

        <p>Regularly included in the most important fictitious characters of all time, discover Derby’s links to the world’s most famous vampire, including Deane’s original adaptation and Bela Lugosi’s performance at Derby Hippodrome.</p>

        <p>The exhibition includes objects on loan from Dacre Stoker, The Dracula Society and The Hammer Script Archive spanning 100 years of Dracula in Derby, a must see for fans of the macabre and Vampire enthusiasts.</p>

        <p>Curated by Derby Museums, presented as part of Dracula Returns to Derby, an AHRC funded research project led by the University of Derby in partnership with Derby Museums, Derby Theatre, Bournemouth University and Sheffield Hallam University. A series of public workshops and events connect the city with the world’s most famous vampire.</p>

        <p>Suitable for all.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Pickford's House<br/>
        Street: 41 Friar Gate<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 1DA
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/dracula-returns-to-derby-101-years-and-counting</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/dracula-returns-to-derby-101-years-and-counting</guid>
      <startDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 30 May 2026 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee, Cars and Chat with Takona</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5517/4411/9703/IMG_4641-20250408144109.JPG?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Coffee, Cars and Chat with Takona"/></p>
        <p>Takona is a name on the car scene you may of heard and exists as the conduit for honest open chat over our favourite subject, cars.<br/>
        Takona, at its heart, is a small clothing brand creating designs to spark conversations around mental health, using cars as the catalyst for connection. Along with its clothing it produces the Takona Tlks podcast and hosts a network of coffees and cars meets around the country.</p>

        <p>Great Northern Classics is pleased to have been added to the handpicked list of venues that hosts these coffee mornings on every second Sunday throughout the year. These are free to attend and all we ask is that your register with us on arrival where you will be greeted by one of our team, of course very happy to chat!</p>

        <p>Grab a coffee and chat cars with Takona!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Great Northern Classics<br/>
        Street: 274 – 278 Osmaston Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE24 8AE
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/coffee-cars-and-chat-with-takona-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/coffee-cars-and-chat-with-takona-1</guid>
      <startDate>Sun, 13 May 2025 09:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The National Forest Walking Festival 2025</title>
      <description>
        Walkers in the National Forest
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/2017/3686/7037/Walkers_in_the_National_Forest.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="The National Forest Walking Festival 2025"/></p>
        <p>This popular annual event, now in its 16th year, offers a variety of trails and experiences for all walking levels and abilities.</p>

        <p>The National Walking month falls during May, and we think this is one of the best times of the year to be outdoors in the National Forest. From the drama of spring blossom, the heady scent of bluebells carpeting ancient woods, and the chance to see wildlife in abundance are all wonderful for the mind and soul.</p>

        <p>If you would like more information regarding the Walking Festival, accommodation, or general tourist information, email: info@visitsouthderbyshire.co.uk</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: The National Forest Walking Festival 2025<br/>
        Street: <!-- Not Provided --><br/>
        City: <!-- Not Provided --><br/>
        County: <!-- Not Provided --><br/>
        Postcode: <!-- Not Provided -->
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/the-national-forest-walking-festival-2025</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/the-national-forest-walking-festival-2025</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 09:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Furnace May Beer Festival</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5317/4065/4513/Furnace_Beer_Festival_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Furnace May Beer Festival"/></p>
        <p>Don't miss the Furnace May Beer Festival! Enjoy delicious food, an incredible selection of cask beers, and a craft keg lineup that's second to none.</p>

        <p>Live music Friday and Saturday.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Furnace Inn<br/>
        Street: 9 Duke Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3BX
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/furnace-may-beer-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/furnace-may-beer-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bearded Theory 2025</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/9217/4058/3530/Bearded_Theory_logo.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Bearded Theory 2025"/></p>
        <p>We’re returning to Catton Park with some incredible acts in tow, join us and join Iggy Pop, Manic Street Preachers, The Sisters Of Mercy, Yard Act, Leftfield, The Mary Wallopers, CMAT, Nova Twins, Ash, Fat Dog plus MANY MANY MORE who we can’t wait bring to the fields!</p>

        <p>…stay tuned for more down the line!</p>

        <p><strong>AVAILABLE TO BOOK NOW:</strong><br/>
        Festival tickets<br/>
        Campervan/Caravan tickets<br/>
        Glamping</p>

        <p>Plus, you can also split the cost of your ticket into monthly instalments with a payment plan</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Bearded Theory 2025<br/>
        Street: Catton Hall & Park<br/>
        City: Walton-on-Trent<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE12 8LN
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bearded-theory-2025</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bearded-theory-2025</guid>
      <startDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whisky in the Woods</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3017/4711/8230/Whisky_in_the_Woods_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Whisky in the Woods"/></p>
        <p>An intimate and laid-back evening hosted by Whisky Ambassador Tom Lindsey and Distller Sarah Mangan.<br/>
        An evening all about sharing whisky in good company. We’ll gather to enjoy six outstanding drams, shared boards of artisanal meats and cheeses and good conversation.</p>

        <p>The drams are carefully curated for a guided tasting through existing, upcoming and prospective Wire Works whisky releases.</p>

        <p>Featuring recently sold out Wire Works Special Waters and a dram from one of our oldest Local Barley casks</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: White Peak Distillery<br/>
        Street: Derwent Wire Works, Matlock Road, Ambergate<br/>
        City: Derbyshire<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE56 2HE
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/whisky-in-the-woods</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/whisky-in-the-woods</guid>
      <startDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 18:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derby Book Festival 2025</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7717/1267/4753/book_festival_logo_thumb_3.jpg?tr=w-390,ar-1-1" alt="Derby Book Festival 2025"/></p>
        <p>The Derby Book Festival will be back for its 10th anniversary in 2025 with their Summer Festival from 23 May – 1 June and their Autumn Edition from 14 – 18 November, with a packed programme of events for all the family.</p>

        <p>The book festival programme appeals to all ages and interests with a range of events, including some with a particular Derby resonance, with themes including railways, science, local history and architecture, cycling, walking, birding, cricket - and even real ale.</p>

        <p>Presenting a broad, diverse programme which attracts internationally renowned writers, poets, historians, politicians, broadcasters, illustrators, storytellers and musicians, whilst also providing support and opportunities for local authors and those taking their first steps towards publishing.</p>

        <p>More information to follow.</p>

        <p>Follow the Derby Book Festival on their social media for more updates or visit their website here.</p>

        <p>Twitter: @DerbyBookFest<br/>
        Instagram: @derby_book_festival<br/>
        Facebook: @DerbyBookFestival</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Book Festival 2025<br/>
        Street: Various Derby venues<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: <!-- Not Provided -->
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-book-festival-2025</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derby-book-festival-2025</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Sheridan: The Red Emperor - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £10
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1917/4367/7845/Michael_Sheridan_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Michael Sheridan: The Red Emperor"/></p>
        <p>Veteran foreign correspondent, Michael Sheridan sheds new light on the history and politics of China, revealing that, behind the façade of the Chinese Communist Party, there is a modern dynasty and a new emperor: Xi Jinping, who became leader in 2012 and presides over 1.4 billion people and the second largest economy on earth.</p>

        <p>Born a ‘princeling’ to one of Communist China’s ruling families, the young Xi was exiled to the countryside during the Cultural Revolution. He fought his way back to the top by stealth, privilege and guile. An absolute ruler, his word is law and he is one of the most consequential leaders of our time. He aims to dominate world trade, to defeat Western democracy and to make China the supreme power in the East.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/michael-sheridan-the-red-emperor-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/michael-sheridan-the-red-emperor-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 18:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Johnson: Harold Wilson - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £12
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/2417/4367/8148/Alan_Johnson_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Alan Johnson: Harold Wilson"/></p>
        <p><strong>Sponsored by Smith Partnership</strong></p>

        <p>Former Labour cabinet minister and best-selling author Alan Johnson returns to the Festival with his latest book, a Westminster Book Award-winner, which chronicles one of the most successful politicians of the 20th century: Harold Wilson.</p>

        <p>Prime Minister from 1964-70, and again from 1974-76, he won four elections as well as a referendum on UK membership of the European Community. The achievements of the Wilson Era – from legalising homosexuality to protecting ethnic minorities, from women’s rights to the Open University – radically improved ordinary people’s lives for the better.</p>

        <p>Alan presents a portrait of a truly 20th century man, whose ‘white heat’ speech proclaimed a scientific and technological revolution – and who was as much a part of the sixties as the Beatles and the Profumo scandal.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/alan-johnson-harold-wilson-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/alan-johnson-harold-wilson-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 20:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faulty Towers The Dining Experience</title>
      <description>
        £49 - £450 + fees
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8317/2828/4273/Fawlty_Towers_Dining_Experience_May_2025_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Faulty Towers The Dining Experience"/></p>
        <p>Direct from London’s Theatreland via the legendary Sydney Opera House, Interactive Theatre International are proud to bring Faulty Towers The Dining Experience, to The Derby Conference Centre on 23 May 2025.</p>

        <p>The world-renowned immersive phenomenon is celebrating 28 years as the world’s most sought-after tribute to the BBC sitcom. Faulty Towers The Dining Experience is an unmissable highly interactive comedy spectacular, where audiences enjoy a 3-course meal alongside 5-star comedy.</p>

        <p>When the audience become diners in the ‘Faulty Towers’ restaurant, pretty much anything can happen – because 70% of the show is improvised. The fun starts as guests wait to be seated. It then hurtles along in a 2-hour tour de force of gags and shambolic service as Basil, Sybil and Manuel serve a ‘70s-style 3-course meal together with a good dollop of mayhem.</p>

        <p>Expect the unexpected!</p>

        <ul>
          <li>‘Immersive theatre at its startling best’ ★★★★★ Best of Theatre, London West End</li>
          <li>‘Fantastic!’ ★★★★★ What’s on Stage</li>
          <li>‘A two-hour eat, drink and laugh sensation’ ★★★★★ The Daily Telegraph</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Conference Centre<br/>
        Street: London Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE24 8UX
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/faulty-towers-the-dining-experience-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/faulty-towers-the-dining-experience-1</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 22:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afternoon Tea with Claire Hubbard-Hall: Her Secret Service: The Forgotten Women of British Intelligence - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £16.50 (includes tea/coffee with scone, jam and cream)
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7017/4427/2086/Claire_Hubbard_Hall_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Claire Hubbard-Hall"/></p>
        <p>Claire will be in conversation with Dr Ruth Larsen, Senior Lecturer in History at the University of Derby</p>

        <p>This event will be filmed and made available as a digital recording after the Festival. Available for purchase here.</p>

        <p>Since the inception of the Secret Service Bureau back in 1909, women have worked at the very heart of British secret intelligence - yet their contributions have been all but written out of history.</p>

        <p>From encoding orders and decrypting enemy messages to penning propaganda and infiltrating organisations, the women of British intelligence played a pivotal role in both the First and Second World Wars. These true custodians of Britain's military secrets include Kathleen Pettigrew, personal assistant to the Chief of MI6 Stewart Menzies, who late in life declared 'I was Miss Moneypenny, but with more power', to Jane Archer, the very first female MI5 officer who raised suspicions about the Soviet spy Kim Philby long before he was officially unmasked and Winifred Spink, the first female officer ever sent to Russia in 1916.</p>

        <p>Drawing on private and previously classified documents, Hubbard-Hall rescues these women from obscurity, bringing their gripping stories to life to provide a definitive account of women's contributions to the history of the intelligence services.</p>

        <p><em>'A fascinating history of the pivotal role played by women in the British intelligence services. A hugely enjoyable read'</em> – Clare Mulley, author of Agent Zo</p>

        <p><em>'Groundbreaking'</em> – Sunday Times</p>

        <p><em>'Beautifully written and elegiac . . . a masterpiece'</em> – Damien Lewis, Sunday Times bestselling author</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Museum of Making at Derby Silk Mill<br/>
        Street: Silk Mill Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/afternoon-tea-with-claire-hubbard-hall-her-secret-service-the-forgotten-women-of-british-intelligence-part-of-summer-derby-book</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/afternoon-tea-with-claire-hubbard-hall-her-secret-service-the-forgotten-women-of-british-intelligence-part-of-summer-derby-book</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May Half-Term at The Children's Country House at Sudbury</title>
      <description>
        Free event (admission applies)
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1116/8235/1766/The_Childrens_Country_House_at_Sudbury_Image_Credit_National_Trust_Robert_Morris.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="The Children's Country House at Sudbury"/></p>
        <p>From 23 May to 1 June, there's something for everyone to get involved in - from following a Blossom Trail throughout the Hall to getting creative in writing workshops.<br/>
        Little ones can let off steam with outdoor games in the Stableyard, while grown-ups can enjoy a treat or two from the cafe.</p>

        <p>The Hall and Museum of Childhood will be open throughout the week for plenty of learning and exploration, and the property will be open daily from 10am to 5pm.</p>

        <p>General admission applies.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: The Children's Country House at Sudbury<br/>
        Street: Sudbury<br/>
        City: Ashbourne<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE6 5HT
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/may-half-term-at-the-childrens-country-house-at-sudbury</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/may-half-term-at-the-childrens-country-house-at-sudbury</guid>
      
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll & Hyde</title>
      <description>
        Standard: £10, Under 26s: £8, University of Derby Students: £5
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4217/4056/8364/Jeykell_and_Hyde_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Jekyll & Hyde"/></p>
        <p>The repression of female voices through the decades gives rise to the Hyde that may just live within us all.<br/>
        In 19th Century Victorian England Harriet Jekyll, desperate to break free of the repressive convention of mourning for her dead husband, seeks excitement from the darkest of places. In the 21st Century, Florence, a young blogger, is accused of provoking an extremist political group to justify acts of violence.</p>

        <p>Evan Placey’s sequel to Robert Louis Stevenson’s horror novella <em>The Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde</em>, presents a modern twist to this most famous gothic horror.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Theatre<br/>
        Street: 15 Theatre Walk<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2NF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/jekyll-and-hyde</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/jekyll-and-hyde</guid>
      <startDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derbyshire Open Arts 2025</title>
      <description>
        Derbyshire Open Arts event artwork
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8817/4678/1633/Derbyshire_Open_Arts_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Derbyshire Open Arts 2025"/></p>
        <p>Join us this late Spring Bank Holiday weekend to meet eight artists showing at Banks Mill, as well as two of our members in their home studios.<br/>
        We will have an exhibition of artwork as well as a kids arts trail for our younger visitors to follow.</p>

        <p>Free parking is available nearby at the Enterprise Centre, 37 Bridge Street as well as pay and display on street parking around the surrounding area.</p>

        <p>Why not visit our affiliate members CRZyBest and Zaza Lewis who are taking part from their home studios, just a few miles away from Banks Mill; as well as Curious Inky Me who will be at Long Eaton Art Rooms.</p>

        <p>Not far away you can also find artists on Bedford Street in Derby, Oakwood, Mercia Marina nr Willington, Long Eaton Art Rooms, Breaston and Ilkeston; that’s a total of 60 artists to meet.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Banks Mill Studios<br/>
        Street: 71 Bridge Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3LB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derbyshire-open-arts-2025</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/derbyshire-open-arts-2025</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 16:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seaside Fun at Crich Tramway Village</title>
      <description>
        Standard Crich Tramway Village admission applies
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5717/4713/7074/Seaside_Event.jpg" alt="Seaside Fun at Crich Tramway Village"/></p>
        <h3>Seaside Fun at Crich Tramway Village</h3>
        <p>Looking for something to keep the children entertained this half term? Crich Tramway Village’s Seaside Fun event could be just the thing.</p>

        <p>This is good old-fashioned seaside fun in the charming countryside setting of the National Tramway Museum in Derbyshire.</p>

        <p>The event runs from <strong>Saturday 24th to Friday 30th May</strong> with various activities throughout the week, including:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Punch ‘n’ Judy</li>
          <li>A flea circus</li>
          <li>Funfair rides</li>
          <li>Crafts</li>
          <li>Sunday bingo</li>
        </ul>

        <p>There’s a purpose-made beach for sandcastle building, as well as a face painter and balloon modeller that are sure to be popular with younger visitors.</p>

        <p>The vintage trams, for which Crich Tramway Village is renowned, will be running daily. If the weather allows, enjoy a ride on an open-top tram with views over the Derwent Valley.</p>

        <p><em>“This event has everything for families who enjoy a great day out with a variety of activities in a beautiful, safe countryside setting,”</em> said Event Manager Candi Bell. <em>“Visitors with valid return tickets can use them during this event, and rides on our vintage trams add to the excitement of the day.”</em></p>

        <p>See the full programme: <a href="https://www.tramway.co.uk/whatson/seaside-fun" target="_blank">www.tramway.co.uk/whatson/seaside-fun</a></p>

        <p>For enquiries, email <a href="mailto:enquiry@tramway.co.uk">enquiry@tramway.co.uk</a> or call 01773 854321.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Crich Tramway Village<br/>
        Street: Cromford Road, Crich<br/>
        City: Matlock<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE4 5DP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/seaside-fun-at-crich-tramway-village</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/seaside-fun-at-crich-tramway-village</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Fun Fair</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7417/4307/5565/Vintage_merry_go_round.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Vintage Fun Fair"/></p>
        <p>Over the May half term we are hosting a Vintage Fun Fair on the Show Field here at Elvaston Castle.</p>

        <p>Opening times 10.30am - 6.30pm each day.</p>

        <p>Normal car park charges apply.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Elvaston Castle Country Park<br/>
        Street: Borrowash Road<br/>
        City: Elvaston<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE72 3EP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/vintage-fun-fair</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/vintage-fun-fair</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 18:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Sinton-Hewitt: One Small Step - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £10
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1617/4367/8553/Paul_Sinton_Hewitt_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Paul Sinton-Hewitt: One Small Step"/></p>
        <p><strong>Sponsored by Pennine Healthcare.</strong></p>

        <p>This is the story of Parkrun, told for the very first time from the man who started it all.</p>

        <p>In search of connection and purpose, Paul came up with a simple idea: he started a free, weekly 5km time trial run every Saturday morning in his local park. Since 2004, it has grown from just 13 runners to a 10 million-strong community across five continents, bringing together people from all walks of life in search of health, happiness and community.</p>

        <p>Growing up in the brutal South African care system, Paul Sinton-Hewitt found solace in running, offering him resilience and a sense of self-worth. Settling in the UK with his family he built – and then lost – a successful career and then a devastating injury threatened to cut him off from his running lifeline. Thus was Parkrun born.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/paul-sinton-hewitt-one-small-step-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/paul-sinton-hewitt-one-small-step-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 12:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 13:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Moss – Ripeness - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £10
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7517/4367/8819/Sarah_Moss_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Sarah Moss – Ripeness"/></p>
        <p>Sarah Moss is consistently cited as one of the UK’s finest contemporary writers and we are delighted to welcome her back following her successful event in 2023 with <em>The Fell</em>. Her latest, eagerly anticipated novel, <em>Ripeness</em>, takes us from 1960s Italy to contemporary Ireland and is a story of love and the search for belonging.</p>

        <p>On the brink of adulthood, Edith travels to rural Italy to help her sister, ballet dancer Lydia, through the final weeks of her pregnancy, help at the birth and then make a phone call which will seal this baby’s fate – and his mother’s.</p>

        <p>Decades later, happily divorced and newly energised, Edith’s life is about to be upended when her best friend Maebh receives a disturbing call from a man claiming to be her brother.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sarah-moss-ripeness-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sarah-moss-ripeness-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gabriel Gatehouse: The Coming Storm - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £10
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/6317/4367/9852/Gabrielle_Gatehouse_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Gabriel Gatehouse: The Coming Storm"/></p>
        <p><strong>Sponsored by Geldards</strong></p>

        <p>Is this how democracy dies? Based on his hit podcast, Gabriel Gatehouse explores the roots of Q Anon and the rise of the extreme right in the US. He takes you down a rabbit hole – one that both the US as a nation and he as a journalist fell through – to unpack an epochal shift in political culture that starts in the earliest years of the Clinton administration and reaches a crescendo on 6 January 2021 with the storming of the US Capitol. But that event was only the beginning of the journey towards another chaotic Trump presidency.</p>

        <p><em>The Coming Storm</em> gets under the skin of these conspiracy theories to show us a radical new kind of politics emerging, a movement that has coalesced around a loose alliance of white supremacists, men’s rights activists, tech bros and radically disenchanted leftists. At a perilous moment in the history of American democracy, Gabriel tells us some dark truths about our present – and provides clues about our future.</p>

        <p>Gabriel will be in conversation with BBC Correspondent Navtej Johal.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby QUAD & Cinema<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AS
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/gabriel-gatehouse-the-coming-storm-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/gabriel-gatehouse-the-coming-storm-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 16:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 17:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruth Amos: The Inventor's Workshop - talk, signing and activities - Part of Summer Derby Book Festival</title>
      <description>
        £8/£20 inc. book
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7517/4419/3367/Ruth_Amos_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Ruth Amos: The Inventor's Workshop"/></p>
        <p>Meet Ruth Amos, inventor and author of <em>'The Inventor’s Workshop'</em>, as she takes a break from YouTube (<em>Kids Invent Stuff</em>) and joins us for invention fun. Learn about the creative sparks that have developed some of the most important inventions into everyday items. After sharing some of these, Ruth will then inspire the children to design their own inventions and create prototypes.</p>

        <p>Suitable for ages 7–12</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Museum of Making at Derby Silk Mill<br/>
        Street: Silk Mill Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3AF
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/ruth-amos-the-inventors-workshop-talk-signing-and-activities-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/ruth-amos-the-inventors-workshop-talk-signing-and-activities-part-of-summer-derby-book-festival</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaam-E-Ghazal</title>
      <description>
        £15.50, Concessions: £12.50
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3717/4530/7763/Shaam_e_Ghazal.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Shaam-E-Ghazal"/></p>
        <p>Experience the soulful magic of ghazals and geet at this specially commissioned Shaam-e-Ghazal evening, featuring talented upcoming vocalists from the East Midlands, Satish Verma and Priya Kaur, accompanied by amazing musicians Kamalbir Singh, Shubham Tajeda & Upneet Singh.</p>

        <p>The evening will pay tribute to reknowned Punjabi poet late Shiv Kumar Batalvi and honour the music of ghazal legends like Jagjit & Chitra Singh, Mehdi Hassan, Ghulam Ali, Madam Noor Jahan and Reshma. If you love the timeless ghazals, this evening is for you! It will transport you to a world of melody and emotion.</p>

        <p>This concert is suitable for age 10+.</p>

        <p>Late comers will not be permitted entry until interval.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Shaam-E-Ghazal<br/>
        Street: 19 Chapel Street<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: <!-- Not Provided -->
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/shaam-e-ghazal</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/shaam-e-ghazal</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crich Tramway Village - Seaside Fun</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8517/3929/0093/Seaside_Event_at_Crich_Tramway_Village_2-20250211160702.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Crich Tramway Village - Seaside Fun"/></p>
        <p><strong>Crich Tramway Village - Seaside Fun!</strong><br/>
        Enjoy the fun of the Seaside with Howard Brothers funfair, Punch and Judy, face painter and balloon modeller and Professor Jon’s Flea Circus (Sat–Wed). Seaside Family crafts every day in the marquee. The daily programme will be listed here nearer the date.</p>

        <p><strong>Ticket Prices:</strong></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adults: £23 pre-booked / £25 on the day</li>
          <li>Children (4–15): £14 pre-booked / £15 on the day</li>
          <li>Family (2 adults, 3 children): £52 pre-booked / £55 on the day</li>
        </ul>

        <p>All tickets include free return within 12 months (subject to opening dates, excluding Premium events).</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Crich Tramway Village<br/>
        Street: Cromford Road, Crich<br/>
        City: Matlock<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE4 5DP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/crich-tramway-village-seaside-fun</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/crich-tramway-village-seaside-fun</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 16:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highland Cow Week</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/2517/4539/0653/Highland_Cow_Week_event_artwork2.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Highland Cow Week"/></p>
        <p>Get ready for a coo-tastic countryside adventure this May half term as we celebrate our fluffiest farm favourites – the Highland cows! With a full week of hands-on activities, adorable animals, and family fun, this is one not to miss!</p>

        <p><strong>Meet the Highland Calves</strong><br/>
        Say hello to our sweetest, shaggy-haired stars! These young Highland calves love a gentle fuss and are ready for selfies, sniffs and even the occasional friendly lick!</p>

        <p><strong>Calf Bottle Feeding</strong><br/>
        Experience the magic of bottle-feeding one of our Dairy or Angus calves – a heart-melting moment for animal lovers of all ages.</p>

        <p><strong>Highland Cow Build-a-Bear (Add-On)</strong><br/>
        Take the fun home by creating your very own cuddly Highland cow! A perfect keepsake to remember your special day. (Available as an optional extra.)</p>

        <p><strong>Highland Cow Safari</strong><br/>
        Hop on our Cow Safari tractor ride and head out to the fields to spot Highland cows up close in their natural environment!</p>

        <p><strong>Sheep Racing</strong><br/>
        They're back and they're speedy! Choose your favourite woolly runner and cheer them on in our hilariously fun sheep races.</p>

        <p><strong>Coo Talks</strong><br/>
        Ever wondered why Highland cows have such long fringes? Learn fun and fascinating facts in our daily expert-led talks.</p>

        <p><strong>Milking Demos</strong><br/>
        Find out how we get fresh milk on the farm with our interactive and educational milking demos.</p>

        <p><strong>Small Animal Petting</strong><br/>
        Cuddle up with our friendly rabbits and guinea pigs, perfect for gentle hands and curious little minds.</p>

        <p><strong>Highland Cow Trail</strong><br/>
        Follow the trail around the farm, complete fun challenges, and see if you can find all the hidden coos!</p>

        <p><strong>Selfie Spots</strong><br/>
        We’ve set up adorable photo points so you can capture the perfect Highland cow memory.</p>

        <p><strong>Sand Art Station</strong><br/>
        Let creativity run wild with Highland cow-themed sand art – take home your masterpiece!</p>

        <p><strong>Go-Karts</strong><br/>
        Race around our pedal go-kart track – a favourite for mini adventurers!</p>

        <p><strong>Indoor & Outdoor Play</strong><br/>
        Rain or shine, we’ve got you covered! Enjoy our giant indoor play barn or head outside to the zip line, swings, and adventure zones.</p>

        <p><strong>The Huge Bouncy Pillow</strong><br/>
        Bounce, leap and laugh on our giant inflatable pillow – fun for kids (and grown-ups too)!</p>

        <p>It’s everything you love about the farm – with an extra helping of Highland fun.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Bluebells<br/>
        Street: Brunswood Farm, Locko Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE21 7AR
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/highland-cow-week</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/highland-cow-week</guid>
      
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bustler's Big Birthday Weekender</title>
      <description>
        £5. Kids free.
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4017/4539/2249/Bustler_Big_Birthday_Weekender_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Bustler's Big Birthday Weekender"/></p>
        <p><strong>IT'S OUR BIRTHDAY!</strong></p>

        <p>Join us for a birthday weekend filled with epic food, family fun and delicious beers & cocktails as we celebrate turning 8!</p>

        <p>Whether you're a foodie, shopper, a music lover, or looking for a family-friendly day out our bank holiday weekend of fun is the place to be.</p>

        <p>Not only do we have Stalls Market bringing a carefully curated independent market to our factory room, we have inflatables, DJ sets, live music, frozen margs and all the party vibes.</p>

        <p>If you've celebrated with us before then you will remember we know how to throw a party - so don't miss out - tickets sold out for our Spring Weekender - you've been warned!</p>

        <h4>Street Food</h4>
        <p>Indulge in a curated selection of the UK's finest street food vendors, with everything from Pan Asian comfort food and delicious shawarma to African fusion bbq and wood-fired pizza.</p>

        <h4>Birthday Giveaways & Party Prices</h4>
        <p>We will be having giveaways throughout the whole weekend - keep an eye on socials for all the details.</p>

        <p><strong>Party Prices</strong><br/>
        2 for £8.00 on cocktails and pints<br/>
        Saturday 7–9pm, Sunday 5–7pm</p>

        <h4>DJ Hudson</h4>
        <p>The DJ Trailer is back to ensure the yard is pumping all day long!</p>

        <h4>Live Music</h4>
        <p>Enjoy acoustic acts throughout the weekend from Carl North and Dorothy Ella (Times TBC)</p>

        <h4>Makers Market by Stalls Market</h4>
        <p>Bringing a talented crowd of 30+ independent businesses for you to browse.</p>

        <h4>Family Entertainment</h4>
        <p>Keep the Bustler kiddo's entertained with inflatables in the factory, arcades, garden games and crafts all day.</p>

        <h4>Inflatables</h4>
        <p>No party is complete without some bouncing fun! You will find a bouncy castle and inflatable carnival games in the factory – 11–5pm both Saturday & Sunday</p>

        <h4>Kids Silent Disco</h4>
        <p>Back by popular demand – Let them dance to all their favourite Disney, Pop & Movie tunes whilst you enjoy the silence!</p>

        <p><strong>Timings</strong><br/>
        Saturday 12–1pm / Sunday 12–1pm</p>

        <h4>Kids Movie Screenings</h4>
        <p>To keep them entertained but calm as the day goes on, we will be setting up mini movie screenings from 5pm both Saturday & Sunday. So you can enjoy the Bustler Party for longer!</p>

        <p><strong>Timings</strong><br/>
        Saturday 5–7pm / Sunday 5–7pm</p>

        <h4>Street Food Lineup</h4>
        <ul>
          <li><strong>English Indian</strong> – An authentic Indian twist on the classic fish & chips</li>
          <li><strong>Kebab Cartel</strong> – Slinging handcrafted Shawarma</li>
          <li><strong>Homeboys</strong> – Pan Asian comfort food – everything from Ramen, small plates & burgers</li>
          <li><strong>Braai Plate</strong> – African-Fusion BBQ</li>
          <li><strong>Kool Kata</strong> – Indian bowls & rolls</li>
          <li><strong>New Yorkshire Pizza</strong> – Wood fired Pizza</li>
          <li><strong>Urban Cheesecake</strong> – The best cheesecakes around</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Bustler Derby<br/>
        Street: The Chocolate Factory, Siddalls Road<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2QD
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bustlers-big-birthday-weekender</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bustlers-big-birthday-weekender</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 11:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Evening with Defying Gravity – West End Women</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8517/3583/1013/An_Evening_of_Defying_Gravity_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="An Evening with Defying Gravity – West End Women"/></p>
        <p>Celebrating women that have made their mark on the West End Stage.</p>

        <p>Join our cast as they perform female led songs from some of the world’s best loved musicals, as well as sharing their own stories and personal experiences from working within the industry – all set in the atmospheric surroundings of the Cathedral.</p>

        <p>Get ready for an unforgettable evening of stunning vocals, backstage anecdotes and fascinating insights into the world of our West End Women.</p>

        <p><strong>Cast subject to change.</strong></p>

        <h4>Venue and ticket information:</h4>

        <p><strong>Tickets</strong><br/>
        Please note that for this performance we are only the hosting venue and we don’t have any association with the tickets for the event. For any ticket enquiries please contact the event company you purchased the tickets through.</p>

        <p><strong>Facilities</strong><br/>
        There is a licensed bar onsite for the performance, cash and card payments welcome. Please note that your own drinks cannot be brought into the venue. The Cathedral management reserves the right to carry out bag searches at its discretion.</p>

        <p><strong>Car parking</strong><br/>
        The nearest car park to the venue is on St Michaels Lane, DE1 3DQ, and is just £2 to park after 6pm.</p>

        <p><strong>Balcony seating</strong><br/>
        The balcony is not suitable for those with access requirements and limited mobility. Patrons on the front row of the balcony must be 16 years of age and upwards. No under 16s will be permitted to sit on the front row of the balcony. Dancing is prohibited on the balcony. If you’d like to dance, we would encourage you to book a ticket in the nave on the ground floor.</p>

        <p><strong>Access seating</strong><br/>
        The Cathedral has provision for a limited number of wheelchairs in the venue, please speak to the box office selling the tickets before booking seats if you require space for a wheelchair or mobility scooter.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Cathedral<br/>
        Street: 18–19 Iron Gate<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3GP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/an-evening-with-defying-gravity-west-end-women</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/an-evening-with-defying-gravity-west-end-women</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bubble Bonanza - May Half-Term</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/3017/4541/2705/Bubble_Bonanza_performer.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Bubble Bonanza - May Half-Term"/></p>
        <p>Get ready for a truly unforgettable day as we bring you Bubble Bonanza, a brand-new event for the farm this May Half Term! We’re thrilled to welcome the incredible SamSam the Bubbleman — a world-famous bubble performer who’s guaranteed to blow you away (literally!).</p>

        <p>SamSam holds 12 Guinness World Records and has wowed audiences across the globe, performing for major brands like Apple, Sony, Sky, Harrods, Toyota, Dyson, and Honda. His spellbinding bubble magic has also dazzled some of the world’s biggest stars including Lady Gaga, Sir Paul McCartney, JK Rowling, and Shakira. Even Royal Families from the UK, Monaco, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Dubai, Abu Dhabi, Mozambique, and Indonesia have experienced his unique brand of bubble brilliance!</p>

        <p>Don’t miss this sparkling, fun-filled day for the whole family!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: National Forest Adventure Farm<br/>
        Street: Postern Road<br/>
        City: Tatenhill, Burton on Trent<br/>
        County: Staffordshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE13 9SJ
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bubble-bonanza-may-half-term</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/bubble-bonanza-may-half-term</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May Half-Term at Chatsworth</title>
      <description>
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8717/4593/2576/Kids_crafting_Image_Credit_Chatsworth.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="May Half-Term at Chatsworth"/></p>
        <p>Enjoy a spring time adventure at Chatsworth, in the heart of the Peak District.<br/>
        Explore miles of walks in our free-to-access park and woodland, look out for wildlife or take part in one of our many creative workshops, tours and activities; there's plenty to keep the whole family entertained.</p>

        <p>Don't forget to visit the farmyard and try out our woodland adventure playground. Our latest arrivals can't wait to meet you, from goat kids to lambs and calves.</p>

        <h4>Family Festival<br/>30 May – 1 June</h4>
        <p>Entry is included with all 'house and garden' and 'garden' tickets.<br/>
        Book your tickets online.</p>

        <p>Our family festival in the garden returns for a second year offering a host of entertainment and activities designed to entertain every family member.</p>

        <ul>
          <li>Master gravity-defying circus skills or watch a big top circus show</li>
          <li>Run for gold in mini Olympic races for all ages</li>
          <li>Join a musical safari</li>
          <li>Be transported to far off lands by story time</li>
          <li>Make and shake your emotions with author Hannah Ormandy</li>
          <li>Take part in workshops by authors/illustrators Lydia Monks and Bethan Woollvin</li>
        </ul>

        <p>Suitable for anyone aged 1 to 101, because who says the wonder of being a child should have an age limit.</p>

        <h4>In the Garden</h4>
        <p><strong>Play in the Pinetum</strong><br/>All day<br/>
        In the majestic surroundings of the Pinetum, test your balance and agility on our natural play equipment.</p>

        <p><strong>Family Trail</strong><br/>All day<br/>
        Follow our family trail to discover the trout stream rapids, fossil spotting, and colourful flowers in the kitchen garden. You can collect a printed map from our house or garden entrances.</p>

        <h4>In the Farmyard</h4>
        <p><strong>Activities in the Oak Barn</strong><br/>10.30am–4pm<br/>
        Play games and or get creative in the Oak Barn.</p>

        <p><strong>Guinea Pig Handling</strong><br/>11.30am, 2pm & 3.30pm</p>
        <p><strong>Chick Handling</strong><br/>10.30am</p>
        <p><strong>Animal feeding</strong><br/>All day<br/>
        Meet our animals up close and feed them a snack while you're here. Pick up your animal feed bag on entry (a small charge for feed applies – add it to your order if you book online).</p>

        <p><strong>Tractor & trailer rides</strong><br/>24 May – 1 June | Various times each day<br/>
        Enjoy a tractor and trailer ride through the park (small charge applies).</p>

        <p><strong>Playground</strong><br/>
        From the farmyard, take the secret tunnel up to the children's playground and enjoy our huge woodland playground, sand pit and water play (waterproofs and wellies recommended!).</p>

        <h4>In the Park</h4>
        <p><strong>Den Building</strong><br/>All day</p>
        <p><strong>Seasonal Nature Spotting</strong><br/>All day</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Chatsworth<br/>
        Street: <!-- Not Provided --><br/>
        City: Bakewell<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE45 1PP
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/may-half-term-at-chatsworth</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/may-half-term-at-chatsworth</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIBE - Garden Party</title>
      <description>
        £4 + booking fee
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/6717/4593/5554/Vibe_Garden_Party_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="VIBE Garden Party"/></p>
        <p>From House, Garage, Jazz, Bass, Dub, we’ve got the juiciest selection of groovy tunes to keep your feet moving and your soul smiling.<br/>
        Dance under the open sky, surrounded by nature, good energy, and even better people. This is more than a party – it’s vibe.</p>

        <p><strong>SEE YOU IN THE GARDEN!</strong></p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Electric Daisy<br/>
        Street: 1 - 4 Bold Lane<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 3NT
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/vibe-garden-party</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/vibe-garden-party</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 22:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Down Brass</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7517/4599/5256/Close_up_of_saxaphone.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Deep Down Brass"/></p>
        <p>Live brass band performing pop hits with a twist.<br/>
        Deep Down Brass bring trumpets, trombone, baritone, sousaphone, and drums – and a whole band full of energy!</p>

        <p>They will be leading you into the Market Hall for our grand opening, entertaining shoppers, and people on the streets, and then giving a stage performance later on!</p>

        <p>Expect a vast repertoire of brassy pop hits – all given the unique Deep Down Brass twist.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/deep-down-brass</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/deep-down-brass</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 11:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:45:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Photograph the Market' - Photography Workshop</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4417/4599/5512/Jon_Legge.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Jon Legge"/></p>
        <p>Want to take better photos? Our Derby Market Hall workshop offers hands-on guidance to improve your photography.<br/>
        Join photographer Jon Legge for a workshop where participants can document the newly refurbished market.</p>

        <p>Open to everyone from complete beginners to photography enthusiasts, we will explore the market hall and take images to share, with expert guidance on technique, composition and how to produce exciting photographs of the opening events.</p>

        <p>It doesn't matter if you use a mobile phone or full digital camera kit, all are welcome!</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/photograph-the-market-photography-workshop</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/photograph-the-market-photography-workshop</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Up Walkabout Show</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/1917/4601/3578/Make_Up_sm.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Make Up Walkabout Show performers"/></p>
        <p>Laugh-out-loud fun with SWANK's pop-up make up salon and nail bar.<br/>
        The big, bold and fully (un)qualified beauticians ‘Cherrie’ and ‘Suzette’ bring you their fully mobile musical make up salon and nail bar.</p>

        <p>Cheesy and fabulously pink, complete with their own range of home blended products ‘Lavatoire de Swank’ the girls bring ‘beauty’ to the masses.</p>

        <p>No challenge too big, no face too small, Cherrie and Suzette perform aura enhancing glitter roll-ons, apply terrible tans and farcical facials, manicures, pedicures and complete make-overs</p>

        <p>These cosmetic clowns celebrate everyone’s beauty, although it’s ‘no good just looking good – you’ve got to feel it within’.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/make-up-walkabout-show</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/make-up-walkabout-show</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 12:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Flower Making Workshop</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/7817/4599/5978/Paper_flower_making.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Paper flower making"/></p>
        <p><strong>Bloom with Creativity</strong> at our paper flyer flower making workshop with FOLK3D at Derby Market Hall.<br/>
        Join the imaginative team at FOLK3D for a delightful workshop in the heart of Derby Market Hall.</p>

        <p>Discover the simple yet beautiful art of transforming ordinary paper flyers into stunning and unique floral creations.</p>

        <p>Learn folding, shaping, and arrangement techniques to craft your own everlasting blooms. This hands-on session is perfect for all skill levels – no prior experience needed!</p>

        <p>Come and enjoy a relaxing and creative afternoon in the vibrant atmosphere of our historic Market Hall. All materials provided.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/paper-flower-making-workshop</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/paper-flower-making-workshop</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 13:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 16:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Granny Turismo</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/2417/4704/5968/Granny_Tarismo_event_artwork.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Granny Turismo event artwork"/></p>
        <p>Hilarious walkabout performance from Granny Turismo.<br/>
        These grannies are out for the day and ready to create havoc.</p>

        <p>They are perched atop their supersized, pimped-up, revving shopping trollies that blast out tunes from Ice Ice Baby to Single Ladies.</p>

        <p>As they screech round corners these ladies are out to have a good time and hopefully trap a toy boy or two.</p>

        <p><strong>Watch out here come the Girls!</strong></p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/granny-turismo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/granny-turismo</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 13:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 16:30:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illustration workshop with Helen Jackson</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5517/4599/6464/Helen_Jackson_illustration.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Helen Jackson illustration"/></p>
        <p>Join illustrator Helen Jackson at Derby Market Hall for a hands-on workshop.<br/>
        Create a little card character of yourself, your friend, your family, someone or something you may find in the Market Hall. Using pencils, pens, imagination and creativity, bring your creations to life, cut them out and add them to the Derby inspired background.</p>

        <p>Suitable for ages 5+ (children accompanied by an adult).</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/illustration-workshop-with-helen-jackson</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/illustration-workshop-with-helen-jackson</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 14:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carl North</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/5517/4599/7110/Carl_North.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Carl North"/></p>
        <p>Experience amazing live music at Derby Market Hall from Carl North.</p>

        <p>Carl North is known well locally, performing regularly at a variety of Derbyshire's well established institutions, and as host of the Dubrek Open Mic.</p>

        <p>Previously the ringleader of the Lonely Hearts, Carl has courted BBC radio play, a long list of festival appearances (including Glastonbury, The Great British Rhythm and Blues Festival and Ynot) and performed the length and breadth of the country alongside a selection of the UK and abroads finest Americana artists. Currently fronting the Derby band Lucille, Carl is working toward 2025 releases and a run of local shows and festivals.</p>

        <p>Carl's infectious energy and diverse song choice, rooted in soul, blues and Americana is the perfect accompaniment to a good nights dance and a sing along.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/carl-north</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/carl-north</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:15:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sura Laynes</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/4717/4599/7305/Sura_Laynes.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Sura Laynes"/></p>
        <p>Live rock and roll music from Derby's very own Sura Laynes.</p>

        <p>Formed in late 2022, Sura Laynes are a rock and roll band from Derby – playing a set for us in acoustic duo format. Their original songs contain strong melodies and lyrics that instantly affect. Clean, crisp guitars and strong vocal harmonies give a nod to the bands that built them, with shades of the La’s, The Libertines and The Beatles detectable in their honest, heart on your sleeve sound.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sura-laynes</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/sura-laynes</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 16:30:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 17:15:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anna Milne</title>
      <description>
        Free
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
        <p><img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/l2o8gnuspz/vd/application/files/8517/4599/7519/Anna_Milne.jpg?tr=w-790,ar-790-495" alt="Anna Milne"/></p>
        <p>Live music from local singer/songwriter Anna Milne.<br/>
        Part of an evening of live music curated by Leah Wilcox.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
      <location>
        Venue Name: Derby Market Hall<br/>
        Street: Market Place<br/>
        City: Derby<br/>
        County: Derbyshire<br/>
        Postcode: DE1 2DB
      </location>
      <link>https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/anna-milne</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.visitderby.co.uk/events/anna-milne</guid>
      <startDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:00:00 GMT</startDate>
      <endDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:45:00 GMT</endDate>
      <geo:lat><!-- Not Provided --></geo:lat>
      <geo:long><!-- Not Provided --></geo:long>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
